Good often folks.
Thank you very much for showing up for yet another session on containers based on the crowd...I can see
that a lot of questions we hope to answer most of your...taylor brown
...matter john we are program manages in the operating systems group at microsoft
...for hyper we and containers.
So, today we're going to learn more about the what why and how let's quickly get started is lot-of
...to cover but feel free to ask questions probably towards the end
once you have...through a bunch of the material we have to go
This is new so please submit your evaluations that would
be awesome we would love to know what a how we can make our ...better.
The key things we want to learn today first step.
Know what containers are.
I would be giving you...incorrect method if I say that you will
...all about containers today but this will make you be intelligent enough
to have a conversation about what contain as essentially to make you dangerous enough to have that conversation
...to the other developers or...it pros
operators or your manages we also gain insight on.
...look at a problem and try to figure out how to solve it is contain
...a tool that you will use the solve that problem and finally
we'll go over what are the main things that microsoft is doing
in this space and will walk you through very quickly all these areas?
So, starting off with let me start with a very quick history intro of
how this whole thing is and where we are in this inflection points?
Way back people used to deal with physical machines people still
deal with physical machines but for the most part developers rarely do it at least the cloud or
datacenter level then came along machine virtualization that changed how people
conceivable looked at datacenters and that brought a lot of innovation yet
disruption that also led to this whole concept of infrastructure as the as a
...arias and that was the early cloud part.
Thank you.
That further gave rise to a services base model where you could have
nudges infrastructure as a service but platform as a service
and software as a service that's pretty much where we are today as
...the concept of containers and throughout the sessions what you learn a is
that as an operating system construct contain
as is not something very new but there's a bunch of things that go into what contain as
is and how it is being used in today's environment that makes it fairly?
Interesting unique and...inflection point and that's where it's in the history in
terms of something that's new and very important for you is
...to understand where it's falling in...
Now if you are not aware of what containers...or maybe this is this...this the
...conferences where you heard about it for the first-time that's completely okay it is something that
people are discovering and we'll keep discovering throughout the whole the next
few years as people try to rather heads around how to use contain is in their environments.
So, what?
So, when people talk about containers there's actually...multiple things when people talk about
...so let me very quickly give you what they are
so at the very basic...is an operating system concept that's
a runtime it's a collection of processes that you
get aggregate in some form...can instantiated and run it on your machine that's
you-can call...the container runtime?
The container image now this is what
you use to distribute or deploy your applications
and there's a layering structure in your images so you have a
...image and then you have an application framework image and then your application image and you
create these images and this is where some of the beauty of what containers
meaning comes into picture where you can distribute just the layer that you
want to distribute and hence make deployment and iteration
of development iteration much faster and then finally.
...a specific spot any
to look at there's a whole notion of image repository how do you get those images that you
have just created and this is a very important part of the whole container ecosystem as
well a container by itself the runtime by itself not very interesting we have
solved that problem decades ago images we have many images
in the industry if it's a vm...ahmed side that's always been
there and distribution mechanism but when you put all of these together
that's when you start seeing something magical happen and that's what we are going to talk about so I'll get
a hand-off to tailor where he's going to start off with a
quick demo show you guys...basic things and then start walking you through how do use
containers how containers can be used in a developers lifecycle?
All right.
Thanks matthew.
So, this thing about this morning...a couple slides we've got some demos
...like demos are better parallel...all right so there's already were to go through the
demos and we're going to go through the slides faster so we get more time for demos
...make some demos up as we go along so it's click over so I've got a laptop here
it's actually running build...server and I've got the why install so those of you who
are here for jeffries session last time you can emulator but,
I'm actually running it so,
that I can do this demo and I've got a virtual machine this virtual machines
...serves our container host it's actually got...inside of it it's got
the darker engine the doctor damon for windows that were working on with stocker
the open-source community running on it so that we can manage the
...creator containers so let's...wrecked that's going to do this
all remotely so this is the darker client running on windows so I can do something like
...images now list the images that I have locally pulled
it right now I've got two I've got a windows server core one I've got one name sys internals.
Now ultimately these will be available in the darker...
you'll be able to pull them down so I could decide hey this is internals once really cool on a
shared up to the doctor have and other people can pull down for now we'll start with
ones we have...actually run container...a darker run
...dashed...or am which just says after this containers exited delete it don't ever want to
see it again it's temporary just get rid of it...dash it which says give me an
interactive consul with this container give the name and then we'll
say what process we want to run so I want to command propped.
...this is doing is actually starting a container so if we looked over at our
...doing a bunch of stuff there we go.
So, how has anybody ever seen windows start that fast?
Now what we've got a full view of windows I can do directory listing I can do all
sorts of stuff but the really cool thing is we sort of a second container
...do it again...run...
Boom...now we're sort of per second dinner.
...starting up let's go over here let's do something like delete everything in the
see drive so it's all gone.
All right we are second...all still there is a completely
individual containers they have their own wvu on the file system and.
For final go ahead and do read...
Delete h
he lm soft where.
I'll recommend this.
Okay, so, let's stray like help known command...
We'll just throw that guy...everything still works over here.
...their own independent view.
They've got their own lifecycle they've got their own session and we'll dive
into a little more that in a moment here.
I think it's important to first kind of look a little
...conference about what the actual lifecycle does this mean for use a developer
...will get through will quicker so we can just more demos but it's important so,
you know, as we think...our lives developer we've got our local machine here we've got nothing on it
...a new project the first question we usually have to answer what am I going to write this thing
in I've got some project I want to what's the language...what's the framework
...js php dot net
whatever that is right we can identify that from...repository like the
...hub and maybe this is actually internal your company maybe someone else's
establish that but the first thing we do is we pulled out.
Now what happens automatically is interdependencies that up
location framework at get automatically pulled in as well as important because
...really means is I don't actually have to care about the dependencies that framework...if
it's no js and needed this version of windows whatever
cool that's great I don't have to care it doesn't matter I stole by just get the
framework igni that's all I have to talk about and this leads to the part of a job that...best
...writing...so we use the exact same development environment exact same tool set now
we've got visual studio for...we can use that that's pretty cool.
Right do everything we just normally would do.
We...code the same way we would or if you're using something like javascript you just, you know,
compilation is that the runtime copied over the exact same process.
The...next steps this is the
...we actually create a container image.
And,...look at this in a demo but...has a language for saying this is how we build an image we
take our compiled code we put that into the container image that container image
expresses dependency it understands the need the application framework application
frameworks says I understand that I need to container os so we push that back into.
Our central repository.
And, thenstart talking to...clicker is just horrible.
On a start talking or other developers now they
couple that and we can do unit testing so actually this is one of course things when you're
writing it how often is a bit test three passes but at least...behind and test seven
then fails common...guys...or even worse.
Because test three ran...test seven passes but it has seven
ran independently we're in trouble...containers we can get a clean.
Environment every time because
...runs exactly the same way every single time no matter where it runs as long as the
data that's been presented to...the same is going to do the exact same thing so we
...unit test in the same way every time we can paralyzing
...can run ten copies of the same time.
We also share with other developers so.
The guy down the hall...run the front-end...use shipping your container image he doesn't have to wait for your build to
get in and then do a local build and I actually got the wrong version and how do I deploy this
you just get the container image and he can do his part of the work independently of you?
You can also stage now...integration qa testing we push
...out...all the device testing qa happens and
it all happens exactly the same will happen on your machine exactly the same way it's going to happen and production.
How many people think
...job is develops how many would say yep I'm dev ops now?
Get more.
Many people...depths a lot more anybody...ops, yeah, one or two.
We talked about the developer par we talked about...the repository the
...hat the...of this is that we figure out how to...this into a...so we
...all the scripts we...all the things that push this into whatever...is as your
...eight of us honestly I don't care we work on the container side of it
...asher but if that's where you're using that's where we're at or your local...
Then we actually figure out how to get analytics right we do some communication they were listening to our customers we
get a bug file something happens that the...need a to make a change.
Just change the container image push the repository and gets pushed out to the
cloud...runs the exact same way now what happens during that we had a
bug some broke so today we get a phone call three o'clock that says hey the
lights down we gotta figure out how to roll back...on...fix do we have to
read deploy everything with containers we just rollback the previous version the container
...still lives in the repository immutable we can just
simply say nope run the other version it'll run exact same way did yesterday before the
fix when we come in the next day we can actually fix the bug and do a redeployment?
So, let's look back over here.
So,...features of windows ten multi desktop and switch between.
So, I've got my.
Code here and I've written a really cool lap.
Or does...line but it's pretty cool if I build this builds
fine and I can kick over to command window and I can run
been debug demo app and sure enough it says it's
a pretty cool out how do I get...new container we talk a little bit a
minute ago about this way to build containers that's called a
doctor file given a make file for container so it's got some instructions
...pretty straightforward it says from windows
server core that's the image that were start from...starting point now if I was using
...application framework no js or something I would say from node js?
And, what that tells dockers...make sure that this images there
...start from if it's not their polit bringing in next thing
...the working directory...all...doing is saying don't...and see windows system thirty-two just
...and sequel the word copy and all of the compile binary
as a set the default command...to be my demo
...command so this is the default you just do run that's what it's going to do?
All right so.
darker bill minus t demo app version one.
So, here goes it's doing to build so insane from windows server core are working directory
its copying over
...code and setting that command so now if we do.
Darker images for
...this new image their dunlap right...so far.
So, we see...
Version one.
we...not container starter demo up inside of it and since I didn't say interactive
...since I didn't specify command it's just going to run and output that.
That something worse that's pretty cool.
But, my app has you...something a little more special so...add some code,
If you're paid attention...the keynote when we actually ran the first container demo you saw that there
...a step in their copying this in ...vcr one twenty
dl there's actually a real example so the whole demo app that we built for the
keynote how-to dependency on that...put...by visual studio so
everywhere it was just working fine because we have visual studio everywhere the web
apples running the first-time we try to put into a container everybody freaked out
...another containers broken...works well, now they just didn't have...dl in...
Right this is exactly an example of that works on my machine goes to production
...doesn't work anymore that's what we had to do to fix the keno demo copy that in so
...that here so I build this guy.
Builds fine.
Go back over if we do or been debug demo
...works here now if we do a darker build.
Minus te demo app to...
Oreos or rebuilding now if I...more steps...here...only actually do the parts...change which is really
cool...done with your doctor images again
now we've got them what to...demo up one.
So, let's do...run.
Now running are...happen.
But, our of containers I can just go back and run version one right-angle fix that I can
define what dependency was needed and go for that
...cool stuff.
So, let's look at...long-lost demo from yesterday.
Artsvia clean image here.
This was the demo the mark wanted to do during the second session but just ran
...time so we've got the system internals image here so what I'm actually going to
...that in build this here.
...doctor history.
And, what is showing us...the history of that image the first thing
...maintain as me and it's the working directory
...copied some stuff over that actually have...all of this internals tools all of the process
explore...object monitor and all that stuff and then it took the...password,
password because I'm super secure are similar there so a number
...good and then I'm sorry the command run to...md and ip can fig
I can see the ip address of the container every container can get its own ip address you can also use
...adding but I can have its own ip its own mac address everything?
So, let's go to run this guy...run.
Like a spans up...the window here.
All right so there we go together container up and running.
It's got...ip address one...sixty-eight zero eighteen and I can
factor into it...go into this internal...
Now if I try to run something likeprocess explore.
Doesn't get much...a ui base tool it has a has a
...associated with it for those of you around...for ...session, you know,
that...like heroine...from the first-time that then they just get worse and worse but,
you know, what kinda...need...right now?
So, first off...the ip address but let's actually show connecting in is container.
So, for those of you don't know you can actually ts into a container.
...tool the tell me with this just wrap around it already but I can actually terms
revenue container...container this is the container video...
Right.
If I make a new file...here so let's say echo of food to
...and hideout text.
Go over here there.
There's my hideout text.
Whatever want to do this though well.
Because I've got a tool like sys internals that I want to run for some reason I
needed to do it maybe has a url...accept.
Boom...container eminences internals on ts than now this is what we're going
to do every day but as we're building images this is actually a very handy
technique as part of the reason we did it...we see inside the container what we see
that we've got a system process we see that we've got services.
...service...but all these things it's pretty cool.
We don't notice is that there's actually two copies of services running there's the
ones in the container there's the ones on the container host five-three containers running
their bthree copies of the services...bone on the house they each have their own
view their own...services their own world
they're completely contained...sharing the kernel so
curl components are shared we get all the density sharing around that but
...user mode the things that matter for most applications completely independent from each other.
Cool stuff.
...excited.
So, we...do more but kickback automatic all right thanks
taylor how is really cool that's the thing that excites me the most of
...the things we can do with it so very quickly let me try to summarize all the
...attributes of containers that...seen so...that's...more.
Yes, maybe I should send your so,
one thing that you just saw was the...iteration the
...which you can speedier development cycle.
It's very easy to create these images it's very easy to deploy
and tested as a developer so that lifecycle is very rapid so that's one.
What we did not see but is a
core aspect of a container runtime is resource control you can
control the resources bead cpu bead memory...storage
or networking any can control it from how much you want to reserve or how much you want to
ltd from using so that's the other big thing that you can start using it?
Deployment a rapid deployment model is something that the operations guy is
concerned about beard bug fixes that's being rolled out or rolling back
...versions of an application that can be run side-by-side throughout the whole
...session you saw how the service architecture allows for these things to happen so contain
is have that attribute...that I can use the existing
...images and the runtime the platform images and
just modify your...layer and...keep deploying it again and again
over and over and the time to deploys much faster earlier you saw the demo during
...talking about how small...images but even that is
...if you have to re deployed every time you have to ship and application that runs analysis so if
you're node years script is fifteen lines of code lead
applying that should not take fifty meg so that's the whole thing about rapid deployment.
Now this is one of those key
attributes of containers maybe it's the key attribute of how you
define your next generation of application which is state separated.
...demonstrate...it I don't know if the nuance was clear for everyone but the
typical use case of a container is.
You create an image you run it whatever gets written
to its local environment...the scratch space you pretty much discarded
unless you are in the process of creating another image but more so the time
at runtime it's supposed to be discarded so essentially what
we're really building...your application of...service that
...building is...separated either it stateless that it doesn't have any state
...just performing tasks.
...you are offering...as part of your starter in either case the
state is separate if you really want to persist information you provide
that information or that the store for a to persist the information that might be on
a network store that might be a locals file of local volume that
...are passing in...to the runtime of the container...the container itself the code that
...written should always assume that it's state separated so that's kind of something
you and, the final thing is immutable itty.
This is again demonstrated when taylor showed how you can
start the same container image over and over and over again and
you're guaranteed to start from the same state and that's a very important aspect
of ensuring that you as a develop of any of develop something
and you have tested in a container environment and you provide that environment
or the image to your production environment
is guaranteed that nothing estrangement binary point of view from the bits point of view from the
...that's in it of course there are aspects of
...that still changes you can still call it state, for example,
you might be running in attest environment with the test network introduction that might
be different network so it's the immutable itty is
in the code in this state that's confined inside the bits of your
condone image but not necessarily completely in the environment so that's something keep in
mind so these are some of the attributes that containers of
...so what are.
The applications that you can think of what does that suit them for and...
I can say that's pretty much everything that you can think of any new kind of problems that
we're thinking of any kind of software that it thinking of writing you should
start thinking about why is that container base environment of micros
...not the right model so you might be building
...distributed computing application...just spread out
...data make sense if you're building a database depending on the kind
of database you have creator if it's a proprietor database
...third-party database you should think about ease the state of the database
that database pog is that separated both from the runtime
can I provide that as a file to my runtime and just instantiate the number
the bits as it comes and goesgreat environment for web if it static or as a serve
as a web worker rule a perfect opportunity is the scalar kind of application where you
...literally providing the...as a scaling out the application
...scaling it back and you just launch as many containers as you want and
the runtime you're saying how many instances you want for whatever kind of
...resources that you're trying to maximize
too and it finally different kinds of task you could be background...
deplore generation a print task any of those things that you field can be
...in the background...great application or use cases for containers.
If you have existing applications that you want to
contain arise these are some of the questions you start thinking of saying how much of
...application is expecting this...to be written bag now one of
the interesting things about containers is also the lifecycle of how you manage the containers.
A traditional virtual machine or physical machine your managing the whole environment you
have your application the application framework the operating system and
year managing and patching and making sure that system lives on so you go
through the reboot...the path cycle and everything else just to support that one application in the
case of containers in the case of container deployments you don't think about those things they are
two distinct scenarios you get your new
base image you get your new application framework you rebuild the package as
...showed it's a darker build.
And,...building an image an image gets deployed probably alongside with the old image.
So, that's until now what we talked about is
...generic containers of most of what we talked about is applicable to
...world as its to windows
will now let me switch gears a bed and talk about what's microsoft doing and,
how is microsoftbringing its own signature
toward to the whole container space so the first thing is?
We actually have to runtime environments some of you heard
...talk about the nano...moment so we have nano server both as a container
hosed on which you can run...and
as a runtime nano server.
A defying.
So,...provides a reduced api set but
a much more tighter set of api is a much more tighter runtime and mom and,
we all love to use the term...in the cloud applications nana server becomes
a perfect environment for you to write your next bottom the cloud application you
should be really you thinking if you don't believe that annals over his
right environments and why not and then we have slower code this is a traditional application
a traditional runtime where you have a higher
comparative existing applications so if you find that you have existing applications
that use the full api said that is provided in
sewer code and you do not want to refactoring application then we have server core as a
runtime as well so...runtime are supported in our container model?
Then we have
the container runtime itself until now we just talked about the
windows server container all the demo that you saw is all about the windows
of a container the windows server container shares the connell
...container runtime has a common colonel with the
container host itself this is very similar to
...pretty much exactly the same as the linux environment where the linux
containers the...created
...they share the same kernel now it has a lot of attributes in terms of
increaase density you get more mobility
...all the attributes we just talked about
...as secure as the operating system I know there's a lot of emphasis that we put in
to windows and to the linux environment to ensure that ...security
vulnerability is left open but it's there so.
So, that's our story in terms of this is...containers and we have our own windows
server containers but when we started down this journey of windows server containers that
bandwidth said shared...and everything else we immediately got feedback and we had our
own internal deployments with as...and hone services very feld.
Some element of tighter isolation
...harder isolation is needed and that was very clearly called
out both internally and as we started exploring
without larger enterprise customers they said,
...web draped contain...a...
Also from...point of view but in terms of a production deployment I need
more I need more isolation well helped me define what
is more isolation...like the vm
base isolation where I know that.
Part of the model of a virtual machine is that even if the virtual machine is running completely
host...code.
Via guaranteeing that.
That posto code can never leaked into the host
or attack the other...machines and people
...to that and they wanted that and they call that that's the level of isolation I won I
won guarantees I want-to make sure that this environment is
cannot affect any other runtime...a okay,
well, that's when we...interestingly microsoft has virtualization technologies and
...proven technology...said let's marry that to let's
Hyper we container and all they're doing with that hyper we container
is we took the windows server container and wrapped it around with the
...hardware-based virtualization extension to ensure that nothing can leak
out so essentially what we're done here is we are not sharing the kernel.
So, container...kernel is not the same as the kernel that's running
inside hyper we container that's a very powerful statement what.
I've just described is
that nothing changed in terms of your experience.
Nothing changed in terms of the image that I had created
nothing changed in my development lifecycle of how why create container images
...just at runtime I can flip a switch...the operations person can flip
a switch based on the policies of the company and
say I want to run that image as a server contain windows
...container or I want to run it as a hyper we containers.
...get compatible benefits in terms of density in terms of
startup time and all the other attributes that I have.
...my workload not change at all those just one flag that chains they have please make
...more isolated.
So, that's essentially what we have done now we are not at
...point where we can demo hyper we containers today that's something we are actively working on
pretty soon later this year we want to start showcasing that.
And, the demo would be pretty uninteresting it
won't look any different than whatever taylor has been talking about like so it will
be pretty boring that's my job to be boring and they could demo.
So, where would you use library containers and, couple of scenarios that we have call
out these this whole environment of multi tendency so if I
have some code that's I want to...the container that's not written by you
...you prefer to...put a tighter isolation boundary and typically multi tenant
environments becomes, becomes top of the prodi that's a perfect use case
...can use that there are other compliance
...use cases where even if you're not running third-party code but you have a
...exposed and you're afraid that someone might sneak into that polled using
buffer role flow whatever else it is and try to get into your container and to your container attack
...container...well if you are paranoid that's another use...for library container?
So, this is where we start talking about the level of
options that you get with whatever via building.
So, we have the different container...that uses exactly the same image
and the same image can be so you could have created that image using hyper
...containers to build all you could have created using windows server
...to build and runtime.
You can choose to run it as a windows of a container or hyper we container.
And, the coolest thing is you could have done the whole you can build
...completely using
a darker api a darker management head using the darker hub essentially creating
...arise...even though underneath
...it's all windows server container all the hyper we container so that's one experience and that's the
experience most people are used to and comfortable but, the same time
...a lot of folks who oscars about ...you going to build a powerful experience because that's what
we're familiar with and yes absolutely we will provide that experience as well
and in fact the architecture that we have built allows for.
A next generation of whoever else wants to come up with and say I have a
new experience for managing containers hey microsoft I want to plea and party on
...as well as...sure.
Just add-on and provide that experience and if it takes all awesome
because that's what we really want enable and I don't know if you guys have.
Internalize that the
...that's the transformation that microsoft is going through
which enables this kind of come builder experience and
we will take you along essentially we are getting to that level of choice.
For our developers for id...for our customers to say we don't want
to tell you it's the microsoft stack on
...essentially we are trying to embrace whatever is out there
whatever makes you feel most comfortable with...development platforms
...environments be management api said whatever it is so
that's one of the thing about the modern development platform moving on to where to a use
containers and this is one of the questions that keep coming up there's always this question about
so,...containers running on physical on vietnam's working to do with it so
very quickly let me walk you through...can be deployed so obviously there's a physical
machine and you can have a virtual machines on the physical machine if...turn on...
You can have hyper be containers running on the physical machine alongside the virtual machines.
You can have windows server containers running
alongside the hyper re containers running alongside
...machines all running on the same physical machine and that's perfectly valid.
Of course the first to require hyper we to be present the hyper we
containers requires the virtualization bits to be present the innovation that we have done with hyper
...and virtual machines require hyper webits as well.
Sorry I'm studying background to get the clicker working.
You could I virtual machines deployed on your physical box.
And, you can deplore hyper...container inside virtual machine.
All you could I would windows server containers deployed inside virtual machines
...spinning ahead of it maybe.
Again, piper we
containers require that hyper vb present inside the virtual machine.
...just an important to know the physical machine notice we didn't say hyper
...require there if you want to run vm
...and run your virtual machine or windows server virtual machine and then put
...inside of that.
Fine you want to run zen km all matters is that the
...typewriter underneath library container is hyper b.
Thank you so.
Yes, so, we need hyper we running to launch hyper be containers
hyper requires virtualization extensions to be present.
Both on the physical...tool
that implies that if you're running hyper we containers in a virtual machine.
Then the underlying virtualization platform needs to support something called nesting.
Method virtualization that's...the virtual machine.
...effectively what have we done.
We have provided a bunch of tools and software that enables a lot of choice.
The choice that you have is you pick the cloud whether it's your public
cloud all your private cloud all the hybrid cloud...you see here is all microsoft
...to be honest when we talk about containers and
...microsoft windows server containers or hyper
we containers didn't really matter.
You could have it on a vm where or a natively
as cloud anywhere that windows server can run you can have
...containers running.
The container technologies the choice that you have you
have linux containers you have windows server
...hyper we add one windows over containers itself.
You have a choice of the management tools that you want to use
...just summarizing what you have...making sure that you understand the different pivot points.
You also have a choice of the development environments and this is very start talking about what is
your favorite tools that eu is to manage and deployed there was.
There was an earlier demo where you could have tightly integrated environment
with visual studio...can just published and,
run the applications the demo you...was that darker and
linux containers the same thing applies to windows containers as well as
long as we maintain the parity of the api the darker api all the tools they
...to that take advantage of the darker api will continue to work with windows,
windows...as well.
Another way to look at the whole thing again
is what are the choices that you have in terms of
containers and other run times.
One of the questions I kept I got...the darker boo...is
...containers competing with service fabric update the same
other different and the answer really is they are all different layers
has software developers you get to choose whether you want to deal with
containers natively all you want to deal with service fabric and billiard applications
...the service fabric level and if you choose to use
service fabric as a platform which you want to billiard applications I would say forget about containers
...fabric will take care of how to run it and where to run it and what is
the right runtime and moment...the choose?
Now the ops guy might have opinions about what level of isolation is
needed and they can tweak it but as developers you should not worry about anything you just
...about your runtime and moment...is and then service fabric will create
the right orchestration model to ensure that you have a...application...
state separated and state consistent application that gets run somewhere but
you might also choose to say nope I want to have my applications run natively as
containers I want to have the control of what the how the
contains a created how this k allowed because I love to do my own organization
absolutely in fact you might choose to use some other orchestration engine that's built
or darker as an ecosystem you might have darker provides their ownthere are other with
needs tools and, cuban eddie's that-you might want-to use as long as
...uses the right supporter api as you can choose that.
Some of having a party.
You can choose to deploying you're applications and this is where it's very important for
you to understand it's not all about
containers it's completely okay to have your workload
...run natively on virtual machines virtual machines are not going anywhere.
So, depends on your use case to figure out
what is the right tool that I have to use it's quite possible that physical
machines out the right environment for you or maybe it's linux virtual machines with no
contain as I don't care about containers that's perfectly fine the choice is still with you?
You have a peter of the development platforms
...languages we are striving to ensure that all of those
continue to work in a microsoft environment a lot of these languages
...these...what natively on windows server you heard
...talk about how we are ensuring that most of this platforms
...times continue to work on nano server all of those would continue to work in a
windows server container and the hyper we container.
So, the choice of your runtime should not dictate what your and result is going
to be so essentially what you're saying and what we're doing is trying to help
you d couple your final destination of
web the application is going to run and make it a very late binding conversation
...binding decision...building...application you might choose to average...the application
...runs on your private cloud that's okay later the policy my changes as I
...move that up to the to the public...because I want to take advantage of the scale my
businesses drawing or maybe I quite a new
...branch office...spread it out perfectly fine?
And, that is the flexibility that you keep getting when you start decoupling
your run-time your development platform and your actual deployment options.
So, summarizing.
I hope, you know, enough about containers at this point that makes you dangers.
I bet you have tons of questions and taylor and I here to also questions
...also has a few demos that we want to go through
this is quickly want to make sure that you understand when to use containers may not use containers how
it is applicable and essentially what microsoft is doing so
...due to the so before we get over this will be in the dec as well
...want to follow-up what's next or documentations
...rsd...go live on monday right now that's going to have like water containers more less what this session
...those kind of questions but this is we have more things available that's what's going to
...follow me on twitter and I will between things out as well but with that
More demos so I literally just wrote some of these...around...talking so we'll see
what they work first there was a show people have gotten this question...where where's the code going for
...very go microsoft slash stocker.
This was the last polarizers merge the master branch but all the real stuff if you really
To see with the nitty-gritty is in this branch jh
argonne, argonne was the code name for windows server
containers...that's where all the codes going that's where all our work on the
...engines going so feel free to go dig around look around now talking to do much without a
build of windows that supports the container primitives that's coming that's coming this summer
...have ever we'll have that build that's where the...come out of that's where all the merges
...back in a darker...minutes I'm like thirty
...requests last week...going back to them pretty rapidly.
So, that let's go over the
...the show is actually how we...container image
...a darker file so there's a step where you can actually say a commit and,
what commit as it makes image so?
Let's make a new a new image solver to do is...do a...around again.
...specify a rm because we actually want
to keep the state we actually want this container to stick around afterward so
that we can take it...with us and we'll say windows server core.
And, we'll do a command prompt.
So,...starting new container from server core.
And, then we're going to install dot net.
I try to install I aspen actually turns out there's a bug right now and I doesn't
...gloriously so we'll skip that will do dot net so
run the same...normally...runt ism so there we go we've
...dot net now we would do is exit so we've
exit container and we get back to darker here second-order see the darker
...ps containers gone if we do a darker ps minus...
containers...are run so the one we want is this guy
hungry...care so,...darker commit.
Of that container image and...will make a new image so if we do
a darker images now...friendly neighbor didn't none and
that's the image id so that's how it actually create an image not using a
...file...a bunch of stuff I could do what I could have run...multiple installs I could
...sorts of stuff but I can also now say darker run
...if I was building another layer application if I was building a new dot net for application or fide
existing done-up for application I can now the install that into this image
and they have a dependency on each other but I've separated the state so if I have another dot net
for application tomorrow I don't actually have to go install dot net again I can just use the same image
and the more commonality you have the more memory where to share what we're going to do is we actually
...this container we go up these are all the files needs
...those of the cache another container starts up
...some of the same files we don't load memory again they're already there we just references
the more commonality have the better the densities going to be the user is to manage.
What I do...container?
As of last week we can we actually have partial working so I can do get
dash item I can do all the normal
powerful things inside of a container of course...our so remote emergency we...
remote connect into a container large want to do that well maybe I should try to trouble shoot something
introducing debugging of an issue you can get into a container and use partial
just fine let's see what else I can do...list.
These...tasks this is actually a cool little
fact see fourteen over here that's actually part of how we're doing the virtualization were
gavin each container instance its own session...if I started up another container.
I team windows server core.
I sort of this new container run tasked we'll see it actually has a different session ideas and a
...process...
So, task.
List we go so we see the system tasks for is actually the same because
that shared...the kernel basically but then...assess as
...mass different and the sessions different each containers its own
...session but we also virtual...actually ask for session zero
can guess what that's what they get they just don't realize they're actually commercialized.
Pretty cool...
We do on time we got a couple minutes left I do...leave of...to payments for questions.
Actually...has...got container up.
As deal domains that's a good curve good question so right now we don't have
...sport and we probably will and everyone and, part of the challenges that containers domains
are kind of different challenge sets right you join a
container the domain and then you turn it off and...someone else and
...ten copies of it active directory doesn't really deal well with having ten machines
the exact same id started up on the same time.
Domain
...they actually are not they're not on domain at all so they just don't show up as domain
...and effectively...now set computer we'll see that it's just got the
...name now we are universal as the host name so I would be able to is part of
running my container say your name on the network is going to be michael website
and we'll redirect as a host name but as an active directory object it's not going to have an identity
today we are thinking about how that will work in the future but for today that's kind of what we think will be?
...have a big licensing question we are not making any
...licensing at this point in time...come in the near future.
...do...handle external dependencies on the network a sequel server there's a couple
answers this question you could actually do it as part of like a doctor composer a
doctor a collection of containers
right actually say the sequel server is one container and it's got...database files may
be externally stored and I've got my web server as the another container and I can actually
...those two together through networking so I can say when you start to look for your data over
here...one modelI think more common models going to be the you actuator sequel server in a virtual
machine because it's the right tool for the job stole or as maybe asher ad
browser database...use point your container at that resource so,
it's got a full network identity so I can run ip...here I can get ip address I can
put on a different network I can use network virtualization all those kind of things...work with absolutely.
What about viruses eml where?
So, we do have as a...talked about before we do have defender running
and every instance of windows including containers
we will have now we're detection running in containers now the cool thing is if you get if
you got a virus or something it's just like the cattle analogy earlier
...start the grill throw-away start another container or
patch the container image and then when I rollers not next containers out and have that
instance addressed that's part of the immutable itty aspect even if you get something in
...to kill it it's gone so next instances start won't have that?
Yes.
So, we...full resource controls the
cpu memory network disk throughput...size as well
...those or at least in the vone we may have some more we probably will have more time.
So, this is kind of interesting questions...nuance so in windows server containers because there's a
share kernel applications inside will generally cv the actual
hard runner underline but,
that's really not the right model and...hyper containers are just going to see virtual
I set of hardware the normally would be there the challenge with using physical hardware is that
kind of break that run anywhere model nominate run anywhere
...this hardware happens be present is configure the right way so, I kinda think the overtime are a little
bit of both but generally we would say avoid...dependencies in hardware.
Right...can also.
Movies...algebraic so the first thing is...both server core and nano server as
container less images...available.
Generally I would say the asher packwood be running on the for on the kind of physical
...the container host the virtual machine is container...
Use to manage containers it probably will not be plugged into the
...tomorrow but over time I think we will do that the
measure services are very much virtual machine specific today and...have to teach
...about containers.
Louis images actually work not even a...container linux images need a linux virtual machine or linux
physical machine...doctor tools we use both but windows containers library
...for windows container images.
How much memory they using so?
We still have a lot of optimizations that we're doing right now the one that I started I think
...was about a hundred-twenty meg.
We also don't have a lot of our
...so...to come around that but we expected...be pretty, pretty good.
Prototype on...type on the same library.
Hyper...hyper wvu on...
Yes.
...container...exactly the same so the easiest way to think about
of a hybrid container for me think about windows server container that's wrapped in a hyper
...partition and literally that's more or less what we've done we've taken windows
server container the exact same runtime and were rapid...and hyper v can partition.
So, what we'll hats they will likely distributed out of
a microsoft place but we're going to make sure there...through doctor hub...a
...windows server core whatever we
...seamless thing but it will actually probably come from a microsoft site?
we are so, we're still working through some...the question hra what's what's the sort of patching.
There's...certain ones how many have to rebuild and that's actually where the doctor file model comes particular
...people checking...the doctor files to the doctor hub so then get rebuilt automatically
that is the ultimate address to a passion scenario because you have if you've got...a base image
the needs to be patched and you don't have any waited to build the instructional top than your
...on patch the stories...very similar to what's happening in the lex as well.
Yes, and, no, depends on how you have build your application if the rebuild of
the image is automated like with the darker build then you can still domain and
ops workflow where they
are as part of every past tuesday or whenever the base image all
the intermediate layers have to be updated is rebuild all image entry
...so the developer doesn't really have to get involved unless and
api is changing in which case years...the developer as to get...
So, the question was what the patch level...difference between the container
host and the container base image...one of the unique differences between windows server
...hyper v container for windows server container they have to match because of the shared
...but if it's a hyper...container the kernel is different so you can
actually have differences in terms of library container can be a different
...patch level or even version level from you container
...I should let you guys go because we are right at the time but,
...hang around here so if you have more questions please do
come by and thank you very much for billion often.